melbourneairport.com.au 2017-10-08

# Privacy policy | Melbourne Airport

This Privacy Policy explains how Australia Pacific Airports (Melbourne) Pty Ltd ACN 076 999 114 (“we/us/our/Melbourne Airport”) manages your personal information.

We are bound by the Australian Privacy Principles of the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) ( **Privacy Act** ) in our handling of **personal information** we collect about you.  We may tell you more about how we handle your information at the time we collect it.

**What is personal information?**

Personal information is information or an opinion about an identified individual, or an individual who is reasonably identifiable from the information or opinion.

**Collecting your information**

We may collect personal information about you when you contact us, visit Melbourne Airport or when you request or use a product or service (for example, the WiFi service or our online parking booking service).

The information we collect may include your name, age, gender and contact details (for example, your home or business address and email address) and location data whilst within Melbourne Airport.  If you visit the airport terminal, we may collect CCTV images of you from our closed circuit cameras.  Our security personnel are equipped with audio-visual recording devices and may record your contact with them for quality, safety and security purposes.  You will be notified orally and in writing before your contact is recorded.  If you login to the WiFi service we provide, we may collect any MAC address associated with your wireless device.  We may also collect information about your interactions with us or the shops in the airport terminal.

Collection of your information may be required by the _Civil Aviation Act 1988_ and the _Civil Aviation Regulations1988_.

If you do not provide some or all of the information we request, we may be unable to provide you with a product or service.

If we receive unsolicited personal information about you (that is information we have not requested), and we determine that we could not have lawfully collected that information, we will destroy or de-identify the information if it is reasonable or lawful to do so.

**Using your information**

We may collect personal information:

•              to assess and process any request you make for services;

•              to provide you with any service you request or assist you with any inquiry you make;

•              to manage our relationship with you;

•              to undertake internal processes including marketing, segmenting, customer profiling, information technology systems   
development, training, statistical research, service improvement and corporate planning; and

•              to identify and (unless you tell us not to) tell you about products and services (including products and services of third parties) that we believe may interest you.

•              To contact you in relation to a competition of Ours you may have entered.

•              for quality, safety security purposes where information is collected by our security personnel.

**Disclosing your information**

We may exchange personal information about you with:

•              our related bodies corporate, assignees, agents, contractors and external advisers;

•              law enforcement, regulatory and government bodies; and

•              reward program providers and promoters of services we provide.

When we disclose your information to third parties, we limit their use and disclosure of that personal information to the specific purpose for which it is disclosed and require them to protect your information in accordance with the _Privacy Act_.

We may disclose your personal information to our systems support service providers located overseas.  The countries to which this information may be disclosed may include the United Kingdom and the United States of America.

**Accessing and correcting your personal information**

We take all reasonable steps to ensure that the information we may collect, use or disclose is accurate, complete and up-to-date.  You have rights to access your information and correct it if it is inaccurate, out-of-date or incomplete.

You may request access to the information we hold about you at any time by contacting our Privacy Officer.  You may contact our Privacy Officer via telephone on (03) 9297 1600 or via email at [**privacy@melair.com.au**](mailto:privacy@melair.com.au).  Alternatively, you may post your complaint, question or concern to the following address:

The Privacy Officer  
General Counsel and Company Secretary  
Melbourne Airport  
Locked Bag 16  
Tullamarine, Victoria, 3043

We will respond to your request within a reasonable time.  There is no fee for making a request but we may charge you the reasonable costs of providing our response to a request for access to personal information.

If we refuse to give you access to any of your personal information, we will provide you with reasons for the refusal and the relevant provisions of the Privacy Act on which we rely to refuse access.

You may also ask us to correct any information we hold about you by contacting us using the details noted above.  We will deal with your request to correct your information in a reasonable time.  If we correct your information and it is information we have provided to others, we will notify them of the correction where we are required to do so by the Privacy Act. 

If we do not agree with the corrections you have requested, we are not obliged to amend your information accordingly, however, we will give you a written notice which sets out the reasons for our refusal.

We will respond to your request to access or correct information within a reasonable time.

**Direct marketing and your information**

We may use your information to advertise or promote products or services (including products and services of third parties) that with your express or implied consent, believe may interest you. We may do this by contacting you, including by telephone or email. With your express or implied consent, we may contact you by telephone even if you are on the Do Not Call Register.

If you do not want us to contact you about products or services you can **opt-out of all further communication** or certain types of communication by contacting our Privacy Officer using the contact details below, or using an unsubscribe facility in an email.

**Website and WiFi**

When you access our website or the WiFi service we provide _,_ we may collect information such as the time and date of your access, your server address and your browser type. When you use the "Contact Us" page on our website we may store any information you send us so we can respond to you if necessary.

We may place and access any cookies on your browser.  We, our service providers or third parties may use cookies to understand your use of our website or our WiFi service _,_ to deliver relevant survey opportunities or for advertising _._ The services we may use from time to time include Google Analytics Advertising Features (Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting, Integrated services that require Google Analytics to collect data via advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers). You can find more details in the privacy policies for those services, including information on how to opt-out of Google Analytics at [ **https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/**](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

Our online __ services may contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or policies of those sites and recommend that you review their privacy policies.

**Complaints, questions and concerns**

If you have any complaints, questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, the use of your personal information, or if you believe that in handling your personal information we have breached the Australian Privacy Principles, you may contact our Privacy Officer via telephone on (03) 9297 1600 or via email at [**privacy@melair.com.au**](mailto:privacy@melair.com.au).  Alternatively, you may post your complaint, question or concern to the following address:

The Privacy Officer  
General Counsel and Company Secretary  
Melbourne Airport  
Locked Bag 16  
Tullamarine, Victoria, 3043

If calling, please request to speak with the Privacy Officer within our Legal Department. 

Once we receive your complaint, we will respond to you as soon as possible and will let you know if we need any further information from you.  We will notify you of our decision within 30 days, however if we are unable to do so, we will let you know the reason for the delay and the expected timeframe to resolve the complaint.

If you are not satisfied with our response to your complaint, or the way in which we have handled your complaint, you may contact the Office of the Australian Information Commissioner, whose contact details are as follows:

**Office of the Australian Information Commissioner**

GPO Box 5218  
Sydney  NSW  2001

1300 363 992

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may, from time to time, update this Privacy Policy without notice to you.  The current Privacy Policy will always be available at **http://melbourneairport.com.au/privacy-policy.html**
